Sub queries can be especially helpful in improving the performance of your queries.
بإمكان الاستعلامات الفرعية أن تكون مفيدة بشكل خاص في تحسين أداء استعلاماتك.
Imagine you're doing some high level reporting for Parch and Posey.
تخيّل أنك تقوم بإعداد تقارير عالية المستوى من أجل شركة Parch and Posey.
You'd like to see a bunch of metrics rolled up on a daily basis.
وترغب في أن يتم إعداد عدة قياسات بشكل يومي.
You could use this to power a dashboard that would help run
يمكنك استخدام هذا من أجل تزويد لوحة معلومات بالبيانات لتساعدك
the business day to day by quickly identifying anomalies.
في إدارة أعمالك اليومية من خلال تحديد مواطن الشذوذ.
To do this, you'll need to join data from a few tables and then aggregate by day.
للقيام بذلك، ستحتاج إلى ربط بيانات من بعض الجداول ثم التجميع بشكل يومي.
You could do all of this in one main query,
يمكنك القيام بهذا باستخدام استعلام رئيسي واحد،
but there are some big advantages to aggregating the tables individually in sub queries,
لكن هناك بعض الإيجابيات الكبيرة لتجميع الجداول بشكل فردي ضمن استعلامات فرعية،
then joining the pre-aggregated sub queries.
ثم ربط الاستعلامات الفرعية التي تم تجميعها.
First, let's look at how we would do this with one big query.
أولاً، لنرَ كيف نقوم بذلك باستخدام استعلام كبير واحد.
One thing you can see here is that to do this properly,
مما يمكنك رؤيته هنا هو أنه للقيام بذلك بشكل صحيح،
we have to join date fields which causes what you might call a data explosion.
علينا الربط باستخدام حقول التاريخ، مما يسبب ما يمكن تسميته بانفجار البيانات.
Basically, what happens is that you're joining every row in a given day from
ما يحدث ببساطة هو أنك تربط كل صف لحدث وقع في أحد الأيام من أحد الجدولين
So the number of rows returned is incredibly great.
أي أن عدد الصفوف التي سيتم استرجاعها ضخم جداً.
Because of this multiplicative effect,
بسبب هذا الأثر المضاعف،
you need to use count distinct instead of
عليك استخدام عد الحقول المميزة count distinct
regular counts to get accurate counts of the sales rep,
بدلاً من العد العادي للحصول على عد دقيق مندوبي المبيعات
the orders, and ultimately, the web visits.
والطلبات، وأخيراً زيارات الموقع.
Just take a look at how big this data set gets before aggregating.
تأمل حجم مجموعات البيانات الضخم هذه قبل البدء بالتجميع.
You can see that executing the join this way returned
يمكنك أن ترى أن تنفيذ الربط JOIN بهذه الطريقة يعرض
79,000 rows which then needed to be aggregated.
79 ألف صفاً يجب أن يتم تجميعه بعد ذلك.
You can get the same result set much more
يمكنك الحصول على النتيجة نفسها على نحو أكثر كفاءة
the counts are performed across far smaller data sets.
بحيث يتم تنفيذ العد على مجموعات بيانات أصغر بكثير.
Here, we have written the first sub query.
كتبنا هنا الاستعلام الفرعي الأول.
And here's the second sub query.
وهذا هو الاستعلام الفرعي الثاني.
As you can see, both of these sub queries are around 1000 rows.
كما ترى، يعرض كلّ من هذين الاستعلامين الفرعيين حوالى ألف صف.
This way, when we write our join,
بهذه الطريقة، عندما نكتب عبارة الربط JOIN،
we'll be joining 1000 onto 1000 rows and
فإننا سنربط ألف صف بألف صف
joining dates onto other dates that match so it would be much less expensive.
ونربط التواريخ بتواريخ أخرى تطابقها،
We're using a full join here just in case
إننا نستخدم عبارة ربط كامل "FULL JOIN" هنا من باب الاحتياط
one table has observations in a month that the other table doesn't.
في حال كانت هناك بيانات في شهر ما موجودة في أحد الجدولين دون الآخر.
As we saw, both sub queries resolved to just about a 1000 rows,
كما رأينا، نتج عن كلا الاستعلامين حوالى ألف صف فقط،
and the final query ends up at just about a 1000 rows as well.
وينتج عن الاستعلام الأخير جوالى ألف صف أيضاً.
So this is a whole lot better than the 79,000 rows that we
وعليه فإن هذا أفضل بكثير من الـ79 ألف صف
saw earlier when we were joining without pre-aggregating in sub queries.
التي رأينها قبل قليل عندما كنا نربط من دون التجميع المسبق في الاستعلامات الفرعية,